<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Andrew Stewart</title>
    <link>https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office for Open Research</title>
      <link>https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/post/2022-06-30-office-for-open-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/post/2022-06-30-office-for-open-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April 2022 the University of Manchester launched the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openresearch.manchester.ac.uk/&#34;&gt;Office for Open Research&lt;/a&gt;. Led by the library, the office supports the University&amp;rsquo;s aims to create a more open and responsible research environment. As institutional lead for open and reproducible research, I work closely with Scott and his team in the library on all aspects of open research, including ensuring that University processes are aligned with our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openresearch.manchester.ac.uk/about-us/position-statement/&#34;&gt;open research position statement&lt;/a&gt;. We have an active network of open research advocates at the University of Manchester, and if you&amp;rsquo;d like to join this network you can subscribe to our emailing list &lt;a href=&#34;https://listserv.manchester.ac.uk/cgi-bin/wa?SUBED1=open_research&amp;amp;A=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see a video of me talking a little bit about open research by clicking &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/wyS7tJPDcq0&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major funding boost for UK’s open research agenda</title>
      <link>https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/post/2022-06-21-major-funding-boost-for-uk-s-open-research-agenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/post/2022-06-21-major-funding-boost-for-uk-s-open-research-agenda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The University of Manchester is one of 18 institutional members of the UK Reproducibility Network (UKRN) receiving significant funding to drive uptake of open research practices across the sector, furthering the UK’s position at the forefront of rigorous and reproducible research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UKRN project “Growing and Embedding Open Research in Institutional Practice and Culture” is worth £8.5M over five years and includes £4.5M from the Research England Development (RED) Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open research ensures transparency across the research lifecycle, promoting rigour, reproducibility, and public trust in research. The benefits of open research practices for improving the quality and integrity of research have been widely documented, and are recognised by the UK Government R&amp;amp;D Roadmap as contributing to improving the culture of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project represents a major strategic investment by Research England that is intended to ensure the UK remains at the forefront of the open research agenda and continues to generate globally leading research of the highest quality. It builds on the recent announcement by the Science Minister regarding UKRI’s new open access policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This funding will drive uptake of open research practices across the UK, through the delivery of training and evaluation of its impact. Initially the project will be delivered across institutions that are part of the UK Reproducibility Network. The network is expected to grow over the five years of the award, making training and material available more widely across the sector.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning R in the Context of Open and Reproducible Research</title>
      <link>https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/post/learning-r-in-the-context-of-open-and-reproducible-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/post/learning-r-in-the-context-of-open-and-reproducible-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2020 I started recording a bunch of workshops as part of two of the Masters level courses I teach at the University of Manchester. I realised they might have broader interest so I decided to share a subset of them via a website. Hopefully you will find them useful. No previous R experience is expected and I take you through all the stages (right from the basics of installing R and RStudio Desktop) step-by-step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just click on the image below to go to the workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://r-openresearch-reproducibility.netlify.app/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ajstewartlang.github.io/images/r_workshops.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image of site&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the material in the workshops was created using open source where possible using an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.entroware.com/store/&#34;&gt;Entroware Apollo laptop&lt;/a&gt; running &lt;a href=&#34;https://releases.ubuntu.com/20.04/&#34;&gt;GNU/Linux distro Ubuntu 20.04 LTS (Focal Fossa)&lt;/a&gt;. The audio was captured with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Condenser-Microphone-Recording-Interface-Power-K669/dp/B01N034RTC/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?crid=141Z8ED4VGCVD&amp;amp;dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=fifine+usb+podcast+condenser+microphone&amp;amp;qid=1594989611&amp;amp;sprefix=fifne+usb%2Caps%2C162&amp;amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUFFMzAxOE5DUDJIREwmZW5jcnlwdGVkSWQ9QTA4MzA2NjIxVU40MlhNMFNCTDhWJmVuY3J5cHRlZEFkSWQ9QTA5NDI2OTQxOFY0R002UVJBS1AzJndpZGdldE5hbWU9c3BfYXRmJmFjdGlvbj1jbGlja1JlZGlyZWN0JmRvTm90TG9nQ2xpY2s9dHJ1ZQ==&#34;&gt;Fifine USB Podcasting microphone&lt;/a&gt; and the video with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Razer-Streaming-Adjustable-Brightness-Microphone/dp/B076QK6489/ref=sr_1_3?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=razer+kiyo&amp;amp;qid=1594989677&amp;amp;sr=8-3&#34;&gt;Razer Kiyo webcam&lt;/a&gt;. The audio and video were recorded using &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com/&#34;&gt;Open Broadcast Software&lt;/a&gt; and edited using &lt;a href=&#34;https://shotcut.org/&#34;&gt;Shotcut&lt;/a&gt;. If you are interested in learning more about open source software, you might be interested in having a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ajstewartlang.github.io/24_open_source/knitted_workshop/24_open_source.html&#34;&gt;this set of resources&lt;/a&gt; I have put together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Beware: Results May Vary” - Workshop on Openness as a Means of Enhancing Research Quality, February 28th, 2020</title>
      <link>https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/post/beware-results-may-vary-workshop-on-openness-as-a-means-of-enhancing-research-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/post/beware-results-may-vary-workshop-on-openness-as-a-means-of-enhancing-research-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question of whether research findings are reproducible (or not) arguably forms one of the core narratives that currently cuts across the boundaries of traditional academic disciplines.  Researchers and funders alike are becoming increasingly aware of how sub-optimal research practices can result in research findings that fail to be reproducible or replicable.  The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bristol.ac.uk/psychology/research/ukrn/&#34;&gt;UK Reproducibility Network&lt;/a&gt; was launched to address these issues and has led to the establishment of Open Science/Research Working Groups across Universities in the UK.  In the North West, we have a hub of such groups and on the afternoon of &lt;strong&gt;February 28th 2020&lt;/strong&gt;, the Software Sustainability Institute and the UK Reproducibility Network will co-host an event (entitled “Beware: Results May Vary”) at the University of Manchester to bring these groups together and focus on openness as a means of enhancing research quality.  The event will consist of a series of talks by researchers from a variety of backgrounds and at different career stages exploring how we can improve the quality of the research we carry out through the adoption of open and reproducible research practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll hear talks about the &lt;a href=&#34;https:www.software.ac.uk&#34;&gt;Software Sustainability Institute&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bristol.ac.uk/psychology/research/ukrn/&#34;&gt;UK Reproducibility Network&lt;/a&gt;, as well as talks on how one early career researcher’s unpublished work ended up on national television, how to empower early career researchers via ReproducibiliTea journal clubs, whether the academic system effectively rewards scientific fraudsters, the role of research software engineers in research, experiences with wrangling (inter)national open science policy, and a keynote talk by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psy.ox.ac.uk/team/dorothy-bishop&#34;&gt;Professor Dorothy Bishop&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Oxford on “Four cognitive biases that make it hard to do science well - and how to overcome them”.  In case you haven’t come across it already, you may be interested in reading Dorothy’s recent piece in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-01307-2&#34;&gt;Nature on (ir)reproducibility in research&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the last talk there’ll be a reception to give people the chance to meet and chat with the speakers and other attendees.  The event is open to everyone with early career researchers being particularly welcome!  Places are limited so please do register via the link in the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://software.ac.uk/beware-results-may-vary-workshop-openness-means-enhancing-research-quality&#34;&gt;advert&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Andrew.Stewart@manchester.ac.uk&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting with the next generation of psychologists in the North West to talk about reproducibility and open research, May/June 2019</title>
      <link>https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/post/lancaster-staffs-keele/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ajstewartlang.netlify.com/post/lancaster-staffs-keele/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last month or so I’ve been fortunate to have given invited presentations to early career psychologists at the universities of Keele, Staffordshire and Lancaster. The combined &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/keele-staffs-joint-psychology-pgr-conference-2019-tickets-57593446549#&#34;&gt;Keele/Staffordshire Psychology Postgraduate Research Conference&lt;/a&gt; gave me the opportunity to provide some (recent) historical context to the current ‘replication crisis’ in the biosciences. A combination of questionable research practices (including p-hacking, and hypothesising after results are known), publication bias (not being able to easily publish null results), and the academic incentive structure (publish or perish!) has created a situation where many published discoveries are likely wrong (that is, the reported findings cannot be replicated and are probably false positives). In response to this, many researchers are now adopting open research practices. These include pre-registration of hypotheses, registered reports (where research papers are unconditionally accepted for publication before data collection begins), reproducible workflows, open data and open code via resources such as OSF and GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my talk, there was a lively discussion with lots of questions from early career researchers about how they might start adopting open research practices and how they might go about learning R. As most psychology undergrads are taught statistics using SPSS, and have little or no coding experience, it’s clear that this is a real challenge. The University of Glasgow provides one possible way forward as their Psychology UG programme involves students learning and coding in R right from the get go. So, it can be done! There was also some discussion about whether the academic incentive structure is beginning to change in a way that will support engagement with open research practices. Given that open research has recently been highlighted as important by REF, we hope that it is beginning to change. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ajstewartlang.github.io/talks/Keele_Staffs_talk.pdf&#34;&gt;You can access the slides from my talk on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ajstewartlang.github.io/images/Lancaster1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several weeks later I was at Lancaster to speak at their ESRC-funded methods workshop on “Future proofing your research” organised by Lancaster’s Open Science Working Group, led by Dermot Lynott. This was a full-day event and featured talks by Kirstie Whitaker (from The Alan Turing Institute) on the Turing Way; Lisa deBruine (from the University of Glasgow) on the Psychological Science Accelerator for multi-lab collaborations; Priya Silverstein (from Lancaster University) on her experiences with the Many Babies multi-lab study; Louise Connell (from Lancaster University) on some of the challenges – and possible solutions – around sharing big data; Josh Sendall and Louise Tripp (Lancaster University) on Open Publishing; and then myself on reproducible data visualisations. Chris Chambers (Cardiff University) joined us for a Q&amp;amp;A on registered reports. Again, there were lots of great questions from the audience (who had travelled from many corners of the UK) with lots of enthusiasm to start engaging with open research practices and interest in working on multi-lab projects. Oh, and the pizza we had for lunch was amazing (thanks Dermot!). &lt;a href=&#34;https://ajstewartlang.github.io/Lancaster_talk/talk_xaringan&#34;&gt;Access the (reproducible) slides from my Lancaster talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the first time I had used the Xaringan markdown template in R to create my slides – given my talk was on reproducibility I thought creating reproducible slides was the least I could do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ajstewartlang.github.io/images/image1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keele and Lancaster Universities are part of our North West Open Research Hub (along with MMU, Sheffield, and Chester) – given the (relative) closeness of these institutions, the Hub provides a great opportunity for the open research communities in each of these places to meet and to share best practice, and run collaborative workshops and events centred on reproducible and open research. If you’re in the North West and want to keep up to date with our open research activities (or are just interested in what we’re up to), please feel free to sign up to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://listserv.manchester.ac.uk/cgi-bin/wa?SUBED1=open_research&amp;amp;A=1&#34;&gt;listserv&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
